[[ {
    "question": "What is a correct syntax to output 'Hello World' in Python?",
    "choices": {
        "a": "echo 'Hello World' ",
        "b": "ec 'Hello World'",
        "c": "printf('Hello World')",
        "d": "print('Hello World')"
    },
    "answer": "d"
},
{
    "question": "What is a correct syntax to the comments in Python?",
    "choices": {
        "a": "/* This is comment */ ",
        "b": "// This is comment ",
        "c": "# This is comment",
        "d": "&lt!-- This is comment -->"
    },
    "answer": "c"
},
{
    "question": "In Python, a variable must be declared before it is assigned a value:",
    "choices": {
        "a": "True ",
        "b": "False"
    },
    "answer": "b"
},
{
    "question": "Which one is NOT a legal variable name?",
    "choices": {
        "a": "Myvar",
        "b": "my-var",
        "c": "my_var",
        "d": "_myvar"
    },
    "answer": "a"
},
{
    "question": "How do you create a variable with the numeric value 5?",
    "choices": {
        "a": "x = 5",
        "b": "x = int(5)",
        "c": "Both the answers are correct"
    },
    "answer": "b"
},
{
    "question": "What is the correct file extension for Python files?",
    "choices": {
        "a": ".pyth",
        "b": ".pt",
        "c": ".py",
        "d": ".pyt"
    },
    "answer": "c"
},
{
    "question": "How do you create a variable with the floating number 2.8?",
    "choices": {
        "a": "x = 2.8",
        "b": "x = float(2.8)",
        "c": "both the answers are correct"
    },
    "answer": "b"
},
{
    "question": "What is the correct syntax to output the type of a variable or object in Python?",
    "choices": {
        "a": "print(type(x))",
        "b": "print(typeof(x))",
        "c": "print(typeofx)",
        "d": "print(typeOfx)"
    },
    "answer": "a"
},
{
    "question": "What is the correct way to create a function in Python?",
    "choices": {
        "a": "function myfunction(){..}",
        "b": "def myfunction():",
        "c": "create myfunction(){..}",
        "d": "void myfunction(){..}"
    },
    "answer": "b"
}],
[
    {
       "question": "Which method can be used to return a string in upper case letters?",
        "choices": {
            "a": "toUpperCase()",
            "b": "upper()",
            "c": "uppercase()",
            "d": "upperCase()"
        },
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Syntax error in python is detected by _________at _______",
        "choices": {
            "a": "compiler/ compile time",
            "b": "interpreter/ run time",
            "c": "compiler/run time",
            "d": "interpreter/compile time"
        },
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question":"What is output for âˆ’ 2 * 2 **3",
        "choices":{
            "a":"12",
            "b":"64",
            "c":"16",
            "d":"36"
        },
        "answer":"c"
    },
    {
        "question":"Which options are correct to create an empty set in Python?",
        "choices":{
            "a":"[]",
            "b":"()",
            "c":"{}",
            "d":"set()"
        },
        "answer":"d"
    },
    {
        "question":"What will be the output of the following code? <br> minidict = { 'name': 'TutorialsPoint', 'name': 'website'}<br>print(minidict['name'])",
        "choices":{
            "a":"TutorialsPoint",
            "b":"Website",
            "c":"('TutorialsPoint','Website')",
            "d":"It will show an Error"
        },
        "answer":"b"
    }
]
]